foreign
[Music]
which stands for study of women's health
Across the Nation is by far the largest
evaluation of menopausal symptoms in
history studying 16 000 American women
between the ages of 40 and 55. they
found that women over a body mass index
of 27 or higher were significantly more
likely to suffer from hot flashes or
night sweats stiffness or soreness and
urinary leakage a BMI over 25 is
considered overweight 30 obese and the
average usbmi 29.8
since fatty tissue is a source for
estrogen one might expect the reverse
but the link between excess body fat and
worse menopausal symptoms indeed seems
causal since women randomized to a
weight loss intervention experienced
significant Improvement in hot flashes
and effect that may extend to bariatric
surgery
in the swan study smoking and inactivity
were also associated with more frequent
symptoms it's always a good idea to quit
smoking and exercise but there are no
Interventional trials on smoking
cessation and menopausal symptoms to
improve cause and effect and randomize
controlled Trials of exercise failed to
show any symptom relief of course you
could just take hormone therapy but at
the cost of significantly higher risk of
suffering a heart attack stroke blood
clot breast cancer or gallbladder
disease what can we do naturally to
avoid the extra clots in cancer hot
flashes also referred to as hot flushes
are the most common menopausal symptom
for which women seek treatment they
flicked up to 80 to 85 percent of
European and American women lasting
along with night sweats for an average
of more than seven years but these
symptoms are not Universal though in
North America they may be considered
inevitable if you noticed in Japan for
example only 15 percent may be affected
in fact there isn't even a term for hot
flash in the Japanese language the
absence of even a word for it in Japan
is all the more remarkable because
Japanese is said to be infinitely more
sensitive than English in describing
bodily states with all sorts of
extremely subtle distinctions for
somatic Sensations for example there's
all sorts of specific terms describing
different Sensations like in Japanese
there are 20 or more words just to
describe the state of one's stomach and
intestines alone
but hot flashes appear to be so unusual
there researchers had to come up with
ways to describe it in Japanese surveys
investigators suspected it might be the
soy
died through surveys have estimated that
soy isoflavon intake the phytoestrogens
and soy is at least 10 times higher than
in Europe or North American one
comparison of Euro metabolites revealed
Japanese women have a hundred times more
phytoestrogens flowing through their
body at any one time
this might be playing a role researchers
followed a thousand Japanese women over
time starting before they reached
menopause to see if soy consumption was
linked to whether or not they developed
hot flashes women eating around four
ounces of tofu a day only had half the
risk compared to women only eating an
ounce or two a day the researchers
concluded our findings suggests that
consumption of soy products is a
practical strategy for preventing hot
flashes but only if Interventional
trials prove they actually work oh which
I'll cover next
before
foreign